should you do organic versus Facebook
ads when you're starting which way
should you start the truth is it depends
and I think you should do both and I'm
going to explain to you in this video
how to not lose a ton of money and
actually make Facebook ads work for you
as well as some strategies for organic
that work and why I think that it's not
a one or the other but rather a both
maybe thing how to make a good decision
as far as when to run ads and what to do
with your organic content to make it all
work for you for those of you who I've
not met yet my name is Jeremiah Kowski
and for the last 21 years I have been
helping marketers coaches mentors
trainers yes the industry existed 21
years ago we used to sell DVD and CD
products back then and I've been helping
them using content creation as well as
marketing advertising Ing and funnel
strategies to scale businesses upwards
to over $20 million per year in profit
and we've done so successfully during
that time and that's what I do is I
bring kind of big Concepts down to earth
to make them simple for you and that's
what today's is uh video is going to be
all about it's going to be kind of down
to earth it's going to be super simple
and easy for you to understand here's
the number one question you have to
answer before you run Facebook ads okay
how much money are you willing to
lose and you might say well I don't want
to lose anything of course who would
want to run a campaign and lose money
but I need you to be a little bit
realistic here to think
realistically okay business is a risk
just stepping outside your front door is
a risk in fact and especially living in
2024 we don't know what's going to
happen running f Facebook ads there is
no guaranteed time no matter how much
success you have no matter how many
years of success or proof or track
record you have to guarantee that
whenever you run an ad campaign that
it's going to make money and you might
say well Jeremiah that sounds easy for
you to say you've been doing it for 21
years uh of course you're you you you
you make it sound so easy because you
got a safety net to fall back on you got
so much experience all that what about
the little guy what about the rest of us
that don't have any money to invest in
ads I I understand because I was there
before and but also here's the thing I
work with hundreds of people that are
coaches mentors trainers authors
speakers incredibly talented smart wise
such amazing human beings and I help
them run Facebook ads that are just
starting out and they come to me to
learn how to not lose money and this is
the first thing that I tell them it's
the first thing that if they can't get
this and by the way I mean I had a
multi-millionaire who literally couldn't
get this and and and and and we had to
part ways because he just the idea of
even losing
$10 baffled him that it was even like
okay to do so that it wasn't considered
irresponsibility okay so I need you to
First address that the only way for you
to make paid advertising work is to have
a set number that you're willing to lose
and you should never run a budget for
your
ads more than what you're willing to
lose so you got to set a budget all the
time when you run ads it's not shouldn't
be flip it it should always be based off
of if I if this campaign produced zero
result would that be okay with
me and if the answer is no then you
shouldn't be running Facebook
ads period
simple and you should focus on
organic however I would challenge you to
say this how many of you have wasted
$100 to interview for a job
before why not then maybe invest 100 to
200 that you are willing to lose even if
you don't get it even if you don't get
the result when running ads and I want
to challenge you in that thinking that
there are things that you do that you
are willing to take take a risk on
because for some reason maybe you feel
more confident in it or things like this
and so this is again what I encourage
people when it comes to Facebook ads you
got to find a number for most people I
tell them that the beginning number
should be right around $500 to ,000 and
this is this is maybe across a period of
1 to two months
okay so that's that's not a lot of money
and I think even in today's
economy you should be able to be able to
find this much with you got to sell some
things whether you got to scr it
together get it together to be able to
test a campaign to test not guess
okay now you might be saying well
Jeremiah if I test it and I'm not
guessing then I should never lose money
again that that thought process that
thinking is flawed to begin with and
it's one of the number one reasons why
people fail and actually do lose money
with a runaway bill when it comes to
their Facebook ads is because they have
this idea that at some moment in time
they're going to know everything that
that is to know when it comes to running
ads but the problem is that they're not
accounting
for
human
un
predictability human
beings you might be might be like well
ai ai Facebook ads yeah what you know
human beings are not
predictable and this is actually a
feature not a bug in the system it's
actually part of our
wiring that when things swing way too
far in One Direction that human beings
usually swing really far in another
Direction we've had a a
surge
of
artificial intelligence over the last
year and in fact most people don't
realize this the AI tools that we have
today have actually been available for
the last three years I've been using
them since March of 2021 in most of our
businesses however AI doesn't work the
way that it did 6 months ago in fact
most AI produced
content doesn't work at all most AI
produced sales campaigns as of today not
6 months ago but as of today will not
produce the result that you're looking
for okay now don't be upset by that
realize it's all a part of human
unpredictability human beings were very
easy to persuade with AI 6 months ago
now they're not because we don't want
machines to control us pretty simple
right we don't want machines to run our
lives how many of you do not want a
machine to run your
life and yet at the same time we have
these little devices right here that
basically run our life to degre but
that's a topic for another time as far
as that
goes so when it comes to running
Facebook ads no matter how much you know
no matter how much experience you have
when it also comes to organic content
when it comes to and really it all boils
down to one of these words that just
everybody loves to
hate algorithms by the way you want to
know what algorithms are they're just
artificial intelligence that's all they
are it's the underlying
AI of the platform that you're
on we're on these platforms here today
where you're engaging we're creating
content we're creating this training
right here and algorithms are what
decide if you're going to actually see
the content or not it's deciding based
on the behaviors that people take and so
if somebody watches your content longer
they're the algorithm says okay let's
find more people like those people and
show this content to them okay when you
run Facebook ads it kind of works the
same way and you can train the Facebook
ads algorithm to show your content to
people that are more likely to buy from
you that's a little bit more advanced
than what I want to talk about here
today and that's something that we
actually go into in my private coaching
Community the client growth accelerator
program again I'm not going to give you
a sales pitch here at all but I just
want to tell you if you go to my website
Jeremiah Kowski decom right here you can
jump on the waiting list for when we
open the doors to my coaching program
where I actually work with you to
develop your sales campaigns your
marketing all of your funnels your sales
copy and actually come alongside you to
build your business this is the program
where we do that to help FastTrack you
towards making 10,000 20,000 $30,000 a
month and even taking that Beyond to
that seven figure level okay and so
that's what this program is you can go
find the info over at my website over at
Jer
mikowski that's where we can really deep
into how do you optimize all of this
it's it's a much more indepth topic and
there's usually a lot of back and forth
conversation that we got to have to make
it all come together for you as far as
that goes it's not super hard to learn
but it does have some Nuance to it that
depends on what your unique individual
business is and that's where we come in
to help help you as far as that goes for
you to decide how much to spend though
you got to make that decision how much
am I willing to lose and really what
we're looking at here is we are looking
[Applause]
at
algorithms that require one of two
resources either
finances or
time
okay and so organic content is going to
take you time investment you may even it
might even take you six to 12 months to
see your organic content start to gain
traction and even then I know people
who've been making daily organic content
for 5 years and they're barely gaining
traction with Organic content if that's
the case for you maybe you've been
trying to make organic content it might
be that you're doing the wrong or old
school way of doing things by the way a
video like this if you're watching this
right now I just want to give you like a
behind the curtain look at what we're
doing and what's working videos like
this it's kind of a long form video
where I got a whiteboard and I'm doing a
teaching that provides value to you
these on YouTube as well as if you're
watching this on Facebook are what is
producing and engaging the best type of
content as well as less is more less
jump Cuts less fancy less Sizzle more
down to earth and authentic why because
people don't want to be controlled by
machines algorithms okay people are
resistant to algorithms controlling
them we have to keep that in our mind in
our Mind's
Eye and now The Jig Is up people know
that there's AI That's helping us create
content they know that the algorithms
are driven by AI they know that the
content is made in a certain way way
that like super heavy High dopamine hit
just makes you feel like you're on drugs
I mean how many of y'all have zoned out
on social media scrolling for hours and
hours and hours just to relax from
anxiety okay and so the problem is with
that is that is becoming less and less
effective and so people are looking for
a different form of connection and the
connection that they're looking for is
authenticity okay so authentic
eity is now what the algorithm is
looking for more down to earth less
polished less
fancy more realistic more legitimate
looking and feeling as far as that goes
okay so as far as organic content goes
you can take time investment you will
have to do manual Outreach to people
such as if people engage with your
content you reach out to them you can
direct message them you can see what
they're up to there are some ways to
automate this which are really kind of
cool and I think that it it is okay to
use some of those tools but be cautious
with some of them as well because they
can remove that human touch and anytime
that we remove the human touch not only
is it the algorithm but it's actually
people's
brains okay we're talking about biology
here people's brains are being wired
differently based on algorithms and they
have just like people might have drug
resistance there is AI algorithmic
resistance that people have where people
become resistant after about 3 to 6
months to a certain way that the
algorithm operates that's why it seems
like the algorithm is changing all the
time it's changing based on human
behavior here's how you know the way
that it's changing what type of content
do you personally engage with
more what type of content are you
watching watching more of does that make
sense okay so because of this we have to
figure out how to get right in front of
the right people in order to sell what
we want to
sell and so you can either buy it you
can pay for it in the form of paid
advertising or you can take time to
create content that feeds the algorithm
What It Wants now here's the thing for
most of us what is natural and authentic
for us often is not prioritized by the
algorithm especially if you're a coach
Mentor or trainer telling people what
they're doing wrong is often our
superpower and yet it's not going to
necessarily go out there to work well
you need to validate what people are
looking for you need to speak to what
their desires are and you need to
actually deliver value in a way that
feels different than everybody else
that's out there and this can be hard
and this is where most people give up
and this is why it becomes a grind for
you to constantly be creating content so
there's really two ways that we grow our
business we can either
purchase
traffic what is traffic traffic can be
considered eyeballs it can be considered
people it can be considered just people
that are on the social media algorithm
that are seeing your content and you can
actually purchase the ability to show
your content in front of of the right
people now here's the
thing this all sounds great but how is
this going to make you any
money it's not in fact that's where most
people get it wrong is they're only
focused on this one part of the equation
they're not focused on how do I actually
make money from it and it's often
because it challenges beliefs that we
believe about our self about our
worthiness and about what's possible
what we should do what are best
practices and we got a whole bunch of
noise inside of our brains that's trying
to convince us that we should be doing
things differently than what actually
works as well if you've ever been sold
by a SL sleazy slimy manipulative
salesperson you don't want to be like
that I don't want to be like that you
don't I guarantee you you don't or you
wouldn't be watching this
video the problem is is this for you to
actually make money you got to sell
something something okay so for your
time investment to be worth anything or
for your financial investment into
Facebook advertising to be worth
anything you need to find a way to
capitalize financially to produce a
return
monetarily from the efforts that you put
into it and maybe some of you you're
like Dove course why would I I wouldn't
be doing this if it wasn't the case some
people like they don't realize that just
putting content out there is not a great
way to make
money the monetization the ads and all
of that on YouTube and Instagram and and
even Twitter uh X all these different
platforms they're not that great when it
comes to actually making you finances
okay so the best way to actually
monetize your business is to have a
product or service and by the way I'm
not a big fan of doing a service based
business because now you're again
trading dollars for hours but sometimes
in the beginning you might need to do a
service-based business sometimes in the
beginning you may need
to do work for somebody in exchange for
a return and so the goal is you got to
create what's called an
offer okay and this is where AI actually
has a superpower is it's really good at
brainstorming offers it's really good at
helping you look at all the different
scenarios and coming up with ideas not
answers and that's key I want you to
realize this AI is good at making and
coming up with ideas to brainstorm to
inspire your own brain not answers or
Solutions
okay say that again and I I need you to
own this one AI is very very good at
brainstorming
ideas
and
possibilities that Inspire your own
brain but it's not good at actually
creating Solutions or final outcomes or
things that you actually put out there
okay and this might sound hard and
difficult but here's the thing we used
to do all of this for the last 21 years
without Ai and it was a lot slower and
so now with AI we can use it to
brainstorm a lot of really cool stuff
and save us literally years of time
testing wishing hoping wondering if
things are going to work out and that is
a win-win for you if you're marketing
because you don't have to waste a like
tens of thousands of dollars in
advertising when you're using AI to help
you brainstorm it can cut that way way
down for you by helping you analyze the
results and put things together and this
is what I break down down with my
clients in my client growth accelerator
this is part of what we spend every
single week working with people on is
developing their
offer helping them put all of this
together we also have a library of
courses that we've actually put together
that help people do this these are
courses that I have taught that are only
available to people in here and one of
the main courses that I love is the six
steps to six figures as a coach it's the
blueprint that I teach everybody when it
comes to creating an effective offer and
whether you're a coach a mentor a
trainer a course creator whether you're
somebody who is just creating content
and you want people to buy it from you
my Niche mostly is people who write
books they do non-fiction they create
some sort of educational content and so
that's why it's called this but this
process really applies to any number of
Industries and so number one you have to
pick your niche
what is the top number one topic or
thing that you can help people with and
often times we can become afraid of
picking the wrong one you want to learn
how to be willing to pick something and
then continue that process next you have
to learn how to write sales copy okay
and what is sales
copy it's a little off there but that's
okay sales copy is the word words that
you use to describe what your offer is
and this is where AI is very powerful at
helping you come up with really really
good unique words to do this in fact we
spent years developing A system that
does this and what's awesome is the AI
is trained on that system that we've
actually developed okay so you can
actually come in there type in what
we've created enter it into there and
then have the AI adjust and tweak it
around our system that we've created
which is amazing which is incredible and
and there's very few people that can
actually say that they've been able to
do that and that's why I think what sets
us apart and makes us unique in what we
teach when it comes to artificial
intelligence after this when it comes to
sales copy is you got to put together
the tech okay so this is your funnel
this is what captures people's info
these are your autoresponders this is
what's going to send the offer to people
and if you're lost in like what any of
this is let me explain this to you a
little bit easier
okay I'm going to flip this page here
and I'm going to show you how this works
okay so number one whether you're
running organic content right this is
like an Instagram reel right here this
is an Instagram reel maybe a Tik Tok
video or you're running a paid ad
campaign this is a Facebook ad right
here
so this is generally going to be some
sort of video content and if you're not
comfortable on video that's a skill set
for you to grow into and it's something
that you can learn to grow into one of
the biggest questions you want to ask
yourself is why am I so afraid to be on
camera what do I think is going to
happen what am I trying to avoid and
often times it answers questions to
where we've let embarrassment come in to
stop us from doing things that are
healthy for us that are going to help us
because we're afraid of what other
people might think
that's again that's an area that I love
to coach my clients on we work with you
through your mindset in my coaching
program so out of this what ends up
happening is whether they're coming from
an organic piece of content or not they
get sent somewhere and this is what's
called a
landing
page and a landing page can be built in
any number of platforms we got stand
store we got kajabi uh think ific
Squarespace clickfunnels uh high level
school all these platforms uh how many
of y'all have seen ads for all these
different platforms out there or even
some of the wh labeled ones from various
influencers that are out there that are
marketing their platforms they usually
got the term 360 at the end of them
generally they're usually a wh labeled
version of go high level if they have
the term 360 at the end of it usually
okay and so off of this though you're
sending people from a piece of content
to an offer page and no matter what what
course you join no matter what Mentor
you listen to no matter who is teaching
it they're all going to tell you to send
people to something that
captures their email
address usually their name and
optionally their phone
number okay so this is contct
information of people that are
interested in the thing that you are
selling so we create an offer right here
that then we send people from a paid ad
to or organic content to and then we get
their contact information now why would
we want this contact information this
creates a really really cool
swirl of experience here and when I'm
saying swirl I literally mean it's like
a swirl like
this it swirls around them where they
end up kind of giving you their info
right here and then they end up you can
run an ad now that you have their info
you can run ads to that person for one
12th of the cost if you have somebody's
contact info the Facebook ads algorithm
lets you run an ad to that person for
generally uh 95% of a
discount than if you don't have their
contact information most people don't
know that and so what I love to do is
get their contact info and then I start
running ads to the same person who I
already got their contact info from at a
major discount okay now I'm obviously
trying to bring more people into this
from running paid ads but this is how we
start to monetize it this is what we
call the
nurture process and so by nurturing the
connection with people we bring them
through this swirl down to our cash
flowing purchasing option but often
times most people are not ready to buy
simply because they opted in so this is
where we might send them an ad then they
might get another email from us we might
make a video on YouTube we send them an
email about that video they see another
ad from us and then they might see oh we
got another Instagram reel and what
happens is they are now in your
ecosystem they have engaged with six
different touch points right here and
what they found is right around six or
seven touch points is where you can
validate that somebody is usually far
more committed and more likely to become
a purchasing client so we can do is we
can actually tag this person right here
we can put a little tag on them
algorithmically and we can tell the
algorithm okay this
person is way more likely to buy from me
than this person so can you show my ad
to people that are more like this person
right here
okay and so then from here what it is is
the algorithm starts tuning in it starts
getting more refined more refined more
refined it ends we end up literally
eliminating half of the funnel the time
and the length of time and this is where
your ads cost starts to come down now
this often can take a few tests to do
this and this is why most people are
like well if I didn't get results the
first time I ran ads bless God I'm going
to throw the baby out with the bath
water kind of hate that term but it's
the best one I
got because it didn't work so what you
got to realize is that that's not
actually how it
works you're going to have to refine a
few things along this process and so
let's go back to our six steps that I
talked about you develop out your Niche
your sales cost of your Tech you start
running your promotion and by the way
this could be organic or paid traffic
and then you make a
sales
pitch of some
kind and this is the part that
challenges most people mentally is
because they don't like selling and they
don't like feeling like they're taking
money from people they feel guilty
asking for money from people let me ask
you this if you're providing value to
somebody for something that they
actually want for something that is
going to make their life better and they
can pay you a fee for it that helps
provide for you and your family don't
you think that that's a win-win for
everybody as far as that goes I think
everybody would say yes of course but
the problem is is that most of us don't
think that what we have is actually good
enough to put out there can I tell you
this that if you have even a a little
bit of a backbone in you and morals and
integrity
what you're going to probably offer
somebody right here is going to be 10
times better than what
most lack of Integrity business owners
that are far more successful than you
and are making way more money than you
are making and so the way I see it is
this I would rather pull business away
from people that have a lack of
Integrity that are manipulating people
that are sleazy that are slimy and not
by doing anything that's unscrupulous or
that I don't feel comfortable doing but
just because we're offering something
better and by simply me being me and
showing up the way that I show up I am
automatically providing a better service
to People by doing that and so if you
can trust that in yourself you can have
a lot more confidence when you come out
there and sell here's the problem though
this doesn't guarantee that you're going
to make any
money we go back to what we talked about
how much are you willing to lose not all
offers are going to make money
and if you think that you're going to
find some method system coach or Mentor
that's going to give you the Magic
Bullet wave at every single offer every
single time makes money I'm sorry I
I that you're believing
lies okay and so I might be the first
person who's out there that actually is
going to tell you that that's not rooted
in
reality and that might be a hard thing
for you to hear especially if you get
drawn to and fro by this coach who's
going to teach you this organic strategy
and this Mentor who's going to teach you
this and this person who says well
people who say that they shouldn't you
listen I'm not here to discredit anybody
as far as that goes I mean there's a lot
of great coaches and mentors out there
and they're helping a lot of
people but what I think is that
sometimes we get tossed to and fro with
way too many
ideas instead of keeping it simple
instead of making it very very easy and
I think that there's way too much
information out there now especially
because of AI and a lot of its low
quality information that doesn't really
help anybody what does work is learning
how to create an offer that is
irresistible to
people that they feel drawn
to and then putting it out
there and learning how do I tune my ad
campaign so that the right people show
up how do I adjust what I say in my
organic content so that I can motivate
people to actually register for the
things that I talk about so that I'm not
wasting my time just flapping my jaws
and talking about stuff and it's not
actually effective here's the thing news
flash here the only reason why I'm
making a video training like this is
because whenever I talk about this stuff
it turns into Good Financial returns for
my business
and so if you want to work with somebody
who's actually done it has a proven
system again like I said I don't have an
opening right now for coaching but you
can jump on my waiting list over at my
website after we go through this process
and listen every single
strategy every single
one whether it be organic or paid
you have to create some kind of a
landing page some kind of an offer where
people sign up for something with you
whether it be free or paid and you have
to learn the art of persuasion you have
to learn how to sell you have to learn
how to take people from being a
stranger right maybe this is the first
time you've seen me ever I'm a a
complete stranger to you I don't expect
you to even join my waiting list you
might think I'm a crackhead for even
saying to join it my last name is Kowski
either
way but how do you take a stranger and
move them along a
path to where the more interactions you
have with them you start building
trust more and more and more and by the
way as you do this your ads cost starts
to come down the amount of money that
you have have to spend on ads to produce
a result starts to come down the amount
of effort that you have to work starts
to come down I only work 10 to 15 hours
a week in my entire seven fig
business and a lot of the businesses
that we've helped and we put together
for people they've been able to work 5
to 10 hours a week to make tens of
millions of dollars whether you just
want to make 5,000 10,000
$20,000 in a business or you're just
getting started or you want to scale you
have have to look at it from this
perspective of going from being somebody
who works in your business to working on
your business and making it
become not the allc consuming focus of
your life but rather something that you
do that you could do if you rolled out
of
bed and you didn't have a bunch of stuff
planned and you could still show up and
crush it and slay it and let me tell you
what I mean by that okay there's a way
that you can actually tune your offer
tune your message tune your ads to where
you don't have to show up as much to
where you don't have to spend as much
time being live with everybody and yet
you can still provide value and here's
what ends up happening is your value
goes up the amount of money you can
charge increases and by the way it's not
exorbitant it's not overinflated to
charge more money as this starts to go
up and what happens is it becomes a
Vortex that sucks people right into your
ecosystem and gets them to buy from you
the better you get at doing one
thing the better all of it starts to
come
together and that
is connecting
with people making a true lasting
connection and connection happens
through emotion and feeling and
experience there's an incredible book
that I absolutely love by an author his
name is John Maxwell called everyone
communicates few connect communication
is what we say out of our mouth
Everybody Talks my one-year-old son
talks but connection goes much deeper to
the heart of the matter and that's what
we are nurturing we are nurtur
nurturing the
connection we're clarifying the signal
how many of yall remember back in the
old days when cell phones weren't that
good and you had to move around to
clarify your connection when it comes to
you getting leads on the internet often
times the signal is a little bit fuzzy
and so as you can start to clarify that
connection things start to be become
crystal clear and what happens is a
trickle of finances starts to turn into
a tsunami of finances and once that
tsunami starts it starts to
snowball bigger and bigger and bigger
and bigger and bigger and things start
to become easier for you you start to
make more money but I'm going to tell
you in the beginning it's not
easy it might actually be the single
hardest thing you've ever done and I
might be making it sound like it's easy
on a training like this it's not I'm not
going to be somebody who's going to lie
to you here there's enough crappy
coaches out there that'll do that I
don't need to do that I've been doing
this long enough to know it's hard
building businesses is
hard but if you can learn a few
strategies that can simplify things they
can change everything for you and that's
what we offer you in my client growth
accelerator program okay so listen we
host Live Events I do videos like this
all the time click the Subscribe button
or follow me to get notified anytime
that I post live videos like this make
sure to open your email and check out we
got a whole series of trainings coming
up here very very soon over the next
month or so that I'm going to be
teaching you and Breaking Down Deeper
these Concepts as well here's what I
want to know from you in the comments
below let me know what other topics
you'd love to see some videos on and I
will literally go ahead and make a
couple trainings based on the most
popular topics that come in okay I'm
excited to do that with you and I'm
excited to work with you on this again
make sure to plug in we got lots of
different resources over at my website
we got a free chat GPT prompt download
right here you can literally go grab
some of the top prompts that we've used
with chat GPT it's a Google doc that
I've actually put together with some of
the very best prompts most people charge
thousands of dollars for this
information and I'm giving it to you for
free right here over at my website as
well as again the waiting list for the
client growth accelerator my private
Elite coaching group we'd love to see
you in there okay have a good one
everybody and I hope that this helped
you in some ways I want to see you
succeed and I believe that if you start
to learn some of the simple strategies
that I've shown you here today about
creating offers and you actually start
to put the pieces
together success is possible for you is
it guaranteed for everybody
no but if if you're willing to do the
work the work is willing to do the
results for you all right I'll see you
in our next video we'll talk soon have a
good one